

IANA LONGO DANDIS

Email: lanadandis98@gmail.com

Address: Dalmine, Bg Born: july 3, 1998

Phone: +39 320 768 9889

Website: https://idandis.github.io/

Github: https:// https://github.com/idandis

About me

I am a computer engineering student who is passionate about improving my technical skills. In my free time, I take various courses on Udemy to expand my knowledge. Along with my studies, I have also been working as a full-stack web developer at Cliccasa.it, gaining valuable experience in the field. I am excited to continue growing and learning in the world of computer engineering

Interests

- Technology
- Nature
- Travel
- Outdoor sports

WORK EXPERIENCE

Science Popularizer at Bergamo Science Center 2017 - 2018

• I acted as a guide for exhibitions and labs at Bergamo Scienza, including math and physics labs

Full-stack web developer for ClicGroup s.r.l. 2021 – Present

Clicgroup s.r.l. is an innovative start-up operating in the real estate sector. It specializes in the development of a real estate portal that allows the publication of properties through collaborations with agencies or individuals throughout Italy, offering various innovative services that facilitate the buying and selling or renting of properties.

- Programming in Python, Javascript, PHP, HTML, CSS
- Database technologies for Web development (SQL)

EDUCATION

Università degli Studi di Bergamo

2019 - Present

Computer Engineering and Applied Sciences

I.S.I.S Luigi Einaudi

2014 - 2019

Scientific high school, applied sciences option.

PROJECTS

Statistics and stochastic models for dataset analysis

<u>https://github.com/idandis/statistics-and-stochastic-models</u>

Analysis on a dataset contains daily data on pollutants and meteorological variables from the Arpa Lombardia website, specifically from the Milano Città Studi Pascal monitoring station, and also data on car travel in Milan based on road directions from Cupertino maps. The goal of the analysis was to identify any relationships between ozone presence in the area and other factors using only descriptive statistics (multiple regression, some advanced regression techniques, and nonparametric techniques) with Matlab.

Statistics and stochastic models for analyzing statistical data and make predictions

https://github.com/idandis/statistics-and-stochastic-models

The project is about analyzing statistical data from the Arpa Lombardia website, which contained a daily collection of atmospheric pollutant quantities and related meteorological variables. Using statistical methods and MATLAB, the goal was to train the predictive capability of the created model using statistical analysis tools and algorithm.

Orienteering live results with a cross platform mobile app

https://github.com/idandis/flutter_orienteering

The project consist in a developed of a distributed system using cloud and mobile technologies, specifically using AWS services (S3 bucket, DynamoDB, JavaScript and Python Lambda functions, and API Gateway) to create a Flutter application using Dart for managing and live consulting the results of an orienteering race.

Dynamic web page that calculate the consumption of methane

https://www.quantospendodimetano.it

Collaboration in the creation of a dynamic web page that allows to calculate approximately the consumption of methane necessary to heat one's home in the colder months, by inserting the energy performance index, the cost of methane, and the square meters of the home.

Java OOP for a video games scheduler

https://github.com/idandis/dandis_iana_info2

An application in Java that manages a set of video game challenges. The application is able to read information from an external text file and manage different schedules for scheduling challenges for competitors, with the ability to add or remove users or new challenges, and manage possible system errors.

Java synchronization methods for a computer laboratory

https://github.com/idandis/synchronous_programming_java

In this project i using java direct or indirect synchronization methods to manage a computer laboratory. In particular, the laboratory is open to an unlimited number of students and has a limited number of workstations. Each student can exclusively use one or two workstations for a limited amount of time. If the workstations are not available, the student must wait. Based on their needs (one or two workstations), students are classified into two different waiting queues, and each queue has different priorities to respect

Speed detection using PCSPIM

https://github.com/idandis/assembly_project_work

The project consist in a program in assembly language using PCSPIM, a MIPS processor simulator, for a speed detection system based on the MIPS R2000 processor (clock speed of 250 MHz). The system utilizes two sensors placed one meter apart that can detect the presence of a vehicle. The program is designed to detect when a vehicle is traveling faster than the 90 km/h speed limit on an rural road. When this occurs, after one second has passed, the program commands the shutter of a camera to take a picture with a 500 ms pulse, and then resumes monitoring for the next vehicle, and so on.

COURSES

The Complete JavaScript Course 2022: From Zero to Expert!

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-3b6ca4dd-d969-4d19-9698-399c052e2f50/

During this course, I developed 6 applications and completed over 50 challenges

SEO Masterclass - Dominate The Search Results

https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-ebadbc64-2e75-4687-a084-cb1f49e274f0/

During this course, i learn the most important aspects of how rank a website in search engines and olso acquire how to optimize every aspect of a website to maximise the chances of earning a high ranking in search results

The Linux Command Line Bootcamp: Beginner To Power User

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-ebadbc64-2e75-4687-a084-cb1f49e274f0/

During this course, i level up my command line skills and also gained new knowledge abount Linux/Ubuntu system

SKILS

Programming languages

Python, Java, Javascript, PHP, C++, HTML, CS

Database

• MySQL, DynamoDB

Other technologies used occasionally

- AWS (apigateway, lamda, bucket S3)
- Flutter & Dart
- Matlab (statistics toolbox)

LANGUAGES

Itaian: Native speaker

Russian: Native speaker

Romanian: Native speaker

English: Intermediate